Paulo Leonardo Benatto

Brighton, UK benatto@gmail.com Phone: +44 07533998484 Post Code: BN1 6AQ

Summary

smeagol@/home/gladden \$ cat profile.txt

Nerd, hobbit, dwarf. These are the words I had heard most when I was a younger. No, don't get me wrong I would be happy to be Froddo, however I think I'm more like Smeagol. Anyway if you don't know what I'm talking about, no worries I'm kinda weirdo $\ddot{\smile}$.

Hi, my name is Paulo Leonardo Benatto, but feel free to call me smeagol. I'm a passionate and eternal learner software developer from south Brazil, but since 2014 I've been living and working in Brighton, UK. In this moment I work at Brandwatch where I'm part of the Core Systems team. What that means? TBH I don't know, but I spend most of my days reading stack overflow (my lover and soulmate), automating tasks using python, some golang and javascript. I also have been learning and working with sensu, puppet and linux.

I'm a good mood guy and I like to think that I'm a people person as well, because I really enjoy working in a team, pair programming, talking about solutions, code and complaining about java (just a joke =).

If you are reading my profile feel free to get in contact or invite me for a barbecue.

Education

Universidade Estadual do Oeste do Parana, BSc in Computer Science, December 2007.

Experience

Futrli

Non 2018 - Present

Python Developer

Main Technologies: Python, AWS, Git;

Python + AWS (Lambda, S3, Step Functions, SNS, CloudWatch, CloudFormation)

Brandwatch Jan 2018 - Non 2018

Javascript Developer

Main Technologies: NodeJS, Python, Linux, Git;

Nodejs + rabbitmq

Brandwatch Jul 2016 - Jan 2018

Core Systems Engineer

Main Technologies: Go, Python, Linux, Git;

I'm part of a team that develops a project called Bigode that is a centralized configuration state aggregator that presents information on all the significant assets in your IT environment. It is part of my day developing REST API in Go, CLI tools in python and some contact with JavaScript to develop the frontend.

Sainsbury's Feb 2016 - Jul 2016

 $Go\ Developer$

Main Technologies: Go, Ansible, Git;

Developing micro-services using Go programming language.

Brandwatch Jul 2014 - Feb 2016

Linux Systems Administrator

Main Technologies: Linux, Python, Bareos, Ansible, Git;

A mix between software development (Python, JavaScript, HTML) and Linux Administration (Debian, Ansible, Puppet, Bareos Backup, Nagios, Sensu, LDAP).

DBA Dec 2013 - Feb 2014

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux, Python, Raspberry PI and C;

Member of a team responsible to design and develop a system to analyse vehicle traffic on Brazilian highways. The product was develop using C, Python and Linux OS.

 $\mathrm{SEC}+$ $\mathrm{Dec}\;2012$ - $\mathrm{Dec}\;2013$

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux, Python, Django Framework, JavaScript and C;

Back-end development of web system for intelligent monitoring and management of natural disasters using Python and the Django framework. Front-end with Javascript (JQuery, Bootstrap, Google Maps API), bJSON, HTML5, CSS. Modeling and use of object-relational database and geographic objects with PostgreSQL/PostGIS.

Digitro Technology - NDS

Jan 2012 - Dec 2012

 $Software\ Engineer$

Main Technologies: Linux, C/C++, Java, ShellScript;

Member of the team responsible to design and develop the roadmap features of a product called Guardião used to intercept calls and internet trafic of people whose are being investigated by the police. Specifically allocated on the design and development of a module which main goal is to intercept the actions done on Facebook, WhatsApp and Hotmail of a target, using the gathered data to cross reference with another possible targets.

Digitro Technology - STE

Set 2008 - Dec 2011

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux, VoIP, C/C++, shellscript, protocols: UDP, TCP, SIP;

Member of a team responsible to design and develop VoIP products such as IP phone and softphone. Most of the projects were developed in C ANSI language under Linux and Windows operating system.

Skills Base

Operating System: Linux (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS), Windows NT/XP/Vista/7 and OSX;

Networkings: TCP/IP protocol suite;

Progamming Languages: C/C++, Python, JavaScript, plus some experience with Go;

Languages: Fluent in Portuguese, Intermediate in English and Spanish;

Open Source Projects

- libpenetra: The libpenetra was created with the goal of studying the windows binary format known as Portable Executable (PE). With libpenetra you can access all information about PE binaries. (https://github.com/patito/libpenetra)
- libmalelf: The libmalelf is an evil library that SHOULD be used for good! It was developed with the intent to assist in the process of infecting binaries and provide a safe way to analyze malwares. (https://github.com/SecPlus/libmalelf)

More Info

- Linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/in/benatto
- Github: https://github.com/patito